Amr Saleh

201-562-7456 | amrsaleh129@gmail.com | http://amrsaleh.me | https://github.com/amrnator

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer who specializes in developing web and mobile apps backed by the cloud. I have a strong background in frameworks like Angular and Ionic 4, and by extension I have a deep understanding of JavaScript and TypeScript. I also have experience in creating machine learning models using Python and TensorFlow. I have a desire to become outstanding in a technical field and excel in a position that allows me to grow and develop.

EDUCATION

Rutgers University

New Brunswick, NJ

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

May 2018

Stevens Institute of Technology

New Brunswick, NJ

Master's in Computer Science

Currently Attending

RELEVANT COURSE WORK

- Introduction to Artificial Intelligence: Machine Learning, AI, Neural Networks, Python and TensorFlow.
- Software Methodology: Design Patterns, Java, JavaScript, Mobile App development.
- Principles in Data and Information Management: Database management systems, SQL, HTML, CSS, JSP.
- Discrete Structures I & II: Discrete Mathematics, Set Theory, Combinatorics, Probability, Statistical Analysis.

EXPERIENCE

Arcane Reality Piscataway, NJ

Virtual Reality Developer – Intern

June 2016 – July 2017

- Implemented features into VR applications and games using C# and C++
- Developed projects in Unity and Steam VR for the HTC Vive and Oculus Rift for technical demos and educational purposes.

The Georgian Society

New Brunswick, NJ

Treasurer May 2017 – May 2018

Managed a ledger, drafted an annual budget, filed property taxes, and handled loans.

Reach Concierge New York, NY

Media Support Analyst

October 2018 – Present

- Acted as a consultant for development on a mobile app using Java/Spring, Ionic 4, PostgreSQL and Angular.
- Implemented analytics, app messaging and notifications using Firebase and Google Cloud Platform.

PROJECTS

Seeker App

- I'm currently developing a mobile app for connecting students to tutors.
- Seeker is a progressive web app built using Angular, Ionic 4 and Firebase.
- Using Google Cloud Platform, I implemented data storage, user authentication, and analytics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages/Frameworks: Java, Python, C, C#, C++, Rust, JavaScript, Typescript, Angular, Ionic 4, TensorFlow.
- Software tools: Git, Bash, Docker, Google Cloud Platform, WordPress, Firebase, Microsoft Office Suite, Unity3D.